# **Danish Hussain**

Email: Dannyh\_786@hotmail.co.uk

## **PERSONAL PROFILE**

I am currently in my final year at De Montfort University in which I am studying a Computer Science (BSc Hons) degree. With excellent communication and organisational skills gained throughout my time at university and work experiences which have also aided me in achieving first class honours in my first two years. I believe that a graduate role would be an excellent opportunity for me to enhance the skills I have acquired till date, whilst also escalating my desire to pursue a career within the technology sector.

## **EDUCATION**

# De Montfort University, Leicester - 2014 - Present

Computer Science (BSc Hons)

#### Year 3:

CTEC3110 - Secure Web Application Development CTEC3426 - Telematics CTEC3903 - Software Development Methods CTEC3905 - Front-End Web Development IMAT3406 - Fuzzy Logic and Knowledge Based Systems IMAT3429 - Privacy and Data Protection	[Pending] [Pending] [Pending] [Pending] [Pending]
IMAT3429 – Privacy and Data Protection IMAT3451 – Computing Project	[Pending] [Pending]
IIVIA 13431 — Computing Project	[Pending]

[Overall: Pending]

#### Year 2:

CTEC2901 - Data Structures and Algorithms	[77%]
CTEC2701 - Multi-tier Web Applications	[60%]
CTEC2602 - OO Software Design and Development (Java)	[71%]
CTEC2121 - Organisations, Project Management and Research	[72%]

[Overall: First]

#### Year 1:

CTEC1901 - Computational Modelling	[72%]
CTEC1412 - Computer Ethics, Law and Portfolio	[65%]
CTEC1801 - Elements of Computing	[83%]
CTEC1401 - Programming in C	[78%]

[Overall: First]

## E-Careers Online - 2014

CompTIA A+ 220-801 – 220-802 – Certificate (Systems)	[Distinction]
--	---------------

## EMBS Training - 2014

ECDL Advance Level 3 Extended Project [Pass]

## Banbury Sixth Form - 2010 - 2012

٨	1
А	Z

AZ		
	English Language	[D]
	Forensic Science	[Merit]
	Philosophy & Ethics	[D]
AS		
	English Language	נחו

English Language [D]
Philosophy & Ethics [C]

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## Sales Assistant - Euro Garages (Esso) - 2014 - 2016

- Enhancing communicational skills through customer queries and customer services.
- Working under pressure whilst ensuring quality standards are met
- Developing time management skills by completing all daily routines according to their specific times

## Supervisor - Martin McColl's - 2011 - 2013

- Gained an understanding of leadership, as well as developing teamwork skills
- Held a higher level of responsibilities, such as carrying out safe checks and banking
- Developed communicational skills through interacting with customers as well as individuals with higher authorities such as area managers

#### Crewe Member - Moto Services - 2010 - 2011

- First experience of working as part of a team
- Dealing with customer queries and complaints, liaising with other departments

#### Work Experience - Matalan - 2009

• First experience of a job and the opportunity to develop an understanding of how the retail organisation works

## **SKILLS/ACHIEVEMENTS**

- Good understanding and experiences of computer languages such as XHTML, CSS, Java,
   C and Haskell
- Excellent understanding in troubleshooting, installations and configurations for desktops
- Project management skills shown through the ECDL Advance Level 3 Extended Project
- Team player with ability to work with minimal supervision and independently
- Ability to develop rapport with clients and professional relationships with ease
- Awarded over twenty commendation certificates throughout secondary school
- Familiar with various operating systems such as Windows/Linux/Unix
- Extensive volunteering experience also have been awarded a gold 150 hours' certificate. Volunteering in places such as prisons, care homes, universities and youth clubs.
- One of the leading faces of the EMBS website to influence new members through my achievements and career goals

## **HOBBIES**

- Exercise such as personal training, running to stay healthy and active
- Reading world affairs, facts, philosophy, the news
- Regular member at the youth club on various community projects (e.g. Shifa Trust)

## **REFERENCES AVAILABLE UPON REQUEST**